Hello English learners, welcome back to EnglishPod.
英语学习者你们好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erica.
我是Erica。
And today we have a very special lesson because we're going to be focusing a little bit more
今天我们有节非常特别的课，因为我们要多花点时间
on grammar.
在语法上。
That's right.
没错。
We're going to look today at the difference between past simple and past progressive or
今天我们要看一般过去时和过去进行时（有时也叫
sometimes called past continuous.
过去持续时）的区别。
Exactly.
正是。
So, we are going to take a look at these two structures which are a little bit confusing
所以，我们要看看这两个有时会让人混淆的结构，
at times and we're going to be practicing today.
今天我们会练习一下。
But before we get started, why don't we take a look at vocabulary preview.
但在开始之前，我们先来看看词汇预览。
Vocabulary preview.
词汇预览。
Well, this dialogue is all about telling a story in the past and we're going to hear
这个对话是关于讲述过去的故事，我们会听到
two words in the dialogue that we need to understand the meaning of.
两个需要理解意思的词。
So, the first one, ages.
第一个词，ages。
Ages.
Ages。
I haven't seen you in ages.
我好久没见你了。
Okay, so if I tell you, I haven't seen you in ages.
好，如果我对你说，我好久没见你了。
Basically you haven't seen me in a really long time.
基本上就是你很久没见到我了。
Okay.
好的。
So, it's a way of exaggerating a little bit.
这是一种稍微夸张的说法。
Yes.
是的。
And this word ages, we can use in many different ways like, I've been studying English for
这个词ages，我们可以用很多不同的方式，比如，我学英语学了
ages.
好久了。
Or for example, I can say, I haven't been to the dentist in ages.
或者比如，我好久没去看牙医了。
Oh, well, guess you better go, huh?
哦，那你最好去一趟，是吧？
Right.
对。
So, ages, a very long time.
所以，ages，很长一段时间。
Yes.
是的。
Now, another phrase, to run into somebody.
现在，另一个短语，偶然遇见某人。
So, to run into somebody.
所以，偶然遇见某人。
I ran into Matt.
我偶然遇见了Matt。
Okay, so if you ran into Matt the other day.
好，如果你前几天偶然遇见了Matt。
You met him unexpectedly.
你意外地遇到了他。
Okay, so you didn't plan to meet, you didn't have a date, you just casually on the street
好，所以你不是计划好的，没有约会，只是碰巧在街上
met.
遇到了。
Exactly.
正是。
Okay, so I ran into your friend the other day.
好，所以我前几天偶然遇见了你的朋友。
Okay, so two good words.
好，两个好词。
We're going to hear both of these in the dialogue.
我们会在对话中听到这两个词。
So why don't we get started with dialogue first time.
那我们开始第一次听对话吧。
Mike, what's going on man?
Mike，最近怎么样，老兄？
Long time no see.
好久不见。
Hey Pat.
嘿，Pat。
Yeah, I haven't seen you in ages.
是啊，我好久没见你了。
How's it going?
最近怎么样？
Things are going great.
一切都很好。
It's funny running into you like this.
这样偶然遇见你真好笑。
Small world, huh?
世界真小，是吧？
You know, just last week I ran into Matt as well.
你知道吗，就在上周，我也偶然遇见了Matt。
Yeah?
是吗？
How's he doing?
他怎么样？
He's doing well.
他过得不错。
We went out for a couple of beers and the funniest thing happened.
我们出去喝了几杯啤酒，然后发生了最有趣的事。
Oh yeah?
哦，是吗？
Well, we were talking and catching up on what we've been doing.
嗯，我们正在聊天，聊聊最近在做什么。
Talking about work and family when all of a sudden Matt saw a mouse run under the chair
聊工作和家庭，突然Matt看到一只老鼠跑到椅子下面，
and he completely lost it.
他完全失控了。
He started freaking out and screaming.
他开始惊慌失措，尖叫起来。
Really?
真的吗？
Yeah, and the funniest thing was then he jumped onto his chair and started shrieking like
是啊，最有趣的是，他跳上椅子，然后像女孩一样
a girl.
尖叫起来。
He should have been there.
你真该在场。
Everyone was staring and laughing.
所有人都在盯着看，哈哈大笑。
It was hilarious.
太搞笑了。
All right, very good, so a funny story and as we saw a lot of stuff in the past, right?
好，非常好，一个有趣的故事，而且我们看到很多过去时态的内容，对吧？
That's right and we're going to look at that in a moment but first we've got lots of exciting
没错，我们一会儿会看这个，但首先我们有很多激动人心的
language to describe when somebody gets really emotional.
语言来描述某人情绪激动的时候。
Okay, so why don't we start now with language takeaway.
好，那我们开始语言要点部分吧。
Language takeaway.
语言要点。
We have four words here.
我们有四个词。
Now in the dialogue, the guy in the story lost it.
在对话中，故事里的那个人失控了。
So he saw a mouse and he completely lost it.
所以他看到一只老鼠，完全失控了。
To lose it.
失控。
Okay, so when you lose something, you lose it.
好，当你失去某样东西时，你就失去了它。
What are you losing?
你失去了什么？
You're losing control of yourself and your emotion.
你失去了对自己和情绪的控制。
Okay, so you lose your temper maybe.
好，所以你可能发脾气了。
Yep.
是的。
So when I lose it, do I just get angry?
所以当我失控时，我只是生气吗？
Or upset?
还是难过？
Or even sad?
甚至悲伤？
But it's usually a negative feeling.
但通常是一种负面情绪。
Okay, so it's not a good thing to lose it.
好，所以失控不是好事。
No, so for example, when I showed my boss the sales figures, he completely lost it.
不，比如，当我给老板看销售数据时，他完全失控了。
Okay, very good.
好，非常好。
So that's what lose it means and now our second word is very similar but has a little bit
这就是lose it的意思，现在我们的第二个词很相似，但有一点
of a difference.
不同。
That's right.
没错。
He started freaking out.
他开始惊慌失措。
Okay, so to freak out.
好，所以freak out。
To freak out.
惊慌失措。
Now freak out is very similar to lose it, right?
现在freak out和lose it很相似，对吧？
Yeah, but why don't we hear an example now of somebody freaking out?
是的，但我们不如听一个例子，看看某人惊慌失措的样子？
It's just, no, no.
就是，不，不。
Okay, forget it.
好，算了。
Forget it.
算了。
All right, just forget it.
好，算了。
I don't even want to just, I just want to forget it.
我甚至不想，我只是想算了。
I just want to forget it.
我只是想算了。
I don't know.
我不知道。
Okay, calm down.
好，冷静点。
Woo.
哇。
Calm down.
冷静点。
I gotta calm down.
我得冷静下来。
I'm so happy.
我太高兴了。
I can't even.
我甚至不能。
I'm so happy.
我太高兴了。
I gotta calm down.
我得冷静下来。
I'm so happy.
我太高兴了。
I can't even express it.
我甚至无法表达。
I'm like, I haven't, have I even finished one sentence?
我就像，我还没，我甚至说完一句话了吗？
I'm like, give me a high five, baby.
我就像，跟我击个掌，宝贝。
All right, so we heard this person freaking out and basically it could be losing control
好，所以我们听到这个人惊慌失措，基本上可能是失控
or losing your temper but also in a positive way.
或发脾气，但也可以是积极的。
Right.
对。
So maybe you're really excited about something that's going to happen.
所以也许你对即将发生的事情非常兴奋。
So you're freaking out.
所以你惊慌失措。
Okay.
好。
Maybe you're very nervous or you're very excited.
也许你非常紧张或非常兴奋。
All right.
好的。
And now moving on to our third word, stare.
现在继续我们的第三个词，stare。
To stare.
盯着看。
People started to stare.
人们开始盯着看。
Staring.
盯着看。
Okay.
好。
Now, when you stare at someone or at something.
现在，当你盯着某人或某物时。
You look at and focus at something for a really long time.
你长时间地看着并专注于某物。
Okay.
好。
So you are looking at it.
所以你在看它。
Yeah.
是的。
Focusing on it.
专注于它。
Yeah.
是的。
Longer than usual.
比平时时间长。
All right.
好的。
Maybe when we were small, our parents taught us that it's not nice to stare at other people.
也许我们小时候，父母教我们盯着别人看是不礼貌的。
Exactly.
正是。
All right.
好的。
So we're going to stare.
所以我们要用stare。
And our final word, when Matt saw the mouse, he started shrieking.
最后一个词，当Matt看到老鼠时，他开始尖叫。
All right.
好的。
So to shriek.
所以shriek。
Shriek.
尖叫。
Very similar to that movie Shrek.
和电影《怪物史莱克》很像。
Oh, yeah.
哦，是的。
It sounds quite similar.
听起来很像。
All right.
好的。
But it's different.
但不同。
What does shriek mean?
shriek是什么意思？
Well, why don't we listen to an example?
嗯，我们不如听一个例子？
Oh my God.
哦，我的天。
Holy chingada.
天哪。
Okay, so I think shrieking is to shout in a very high pitched voice.
好，所以我认为尖叫是用很高的声音喊叫。
Exactly.
正是。
That's to shriek.
这就是shriek。
Okay.
好。
So we saw four really great words in language takeaway.
所以我们在语言要点中看到了四个非常好的词。
And why don't we listen now to the dialogue for a second time, a little bit slower.
我们现在再听一遍对话，稍微慢一点。
And then we'll come back and look at the differences between simple past and past progressive.
然后我们回来看看一般过去时和过去进行时的区别。
Mike, what's going on, man?
Mike，最近怎么样，老兄？
Long time no see.
好久不见。
Hey, Pat.
嘿，Pat。
Yeah, I haven't seen you in ages.
是啊，我好久没见你了。
How's it going?
最近怎么样？
Things are going great.
一切都很好。
It's funny running into you like this.
这样偶然遇见你真好笑。
Small world, eh?
世界真小，是吧？
You know, just last week, I ran into Matt as well.
你知道吗，就在上周，我也偶然遇见了Matt。
Yeah?
是吗？
How's he doing?
他怎么样？
He's doing well.
他过得不错。
We went out for a couple of beers and the funniest thing happened.
我们出去喝了几杯啤酒，然后发生了最有趣的事。
Oh, yeah?
哦，是吗？
Well, we were talking and catching up on what we've been doing.
嗯，我们正在聊天，聊聊最近在做什么。
Talking about work and family, when all of a sudden, Matt's all mouse run under his chair
聊工作和家庭，突然Matt看到一只老鼠跑到椅子下面，
and he completely lost it.
他完全失控了。
He started freaking out and screaming.
他开始惊慌失措，尖叫起来。
Really?
真的吗？
Yeah.
是啊。
And the funniest thing was that he jumped on his chair and started shrieking like a
最有趣的是，他跳上椅子，然后像女孩一样
girl.
尖叫起来。
You should have been there.
你真该在场。
Everyone was staring and laughing.
所有人都在盯着看，哈哈大笑。
It was hilarious.
太搞笑了。
Okay, so there was a lot of different uses of past tense here in this dialogue, wasn't
好，所以这个对话里有很多不同的过去时态用法，对吧？
there?
对吧？
When he was telling a story that happened, he used the past a lot.
当他讲一个发生过的故事时，他用了很多过去时。
Well, let's now, as promised, look at past simple and past progressive in Grammar Breakdown.
好，我们现在按承诺，在语法解析中看看一般过去时和过去进行时。
Grammar Breakdown.
语法解析。
Okay, Marco, before we start our discussion, why don't we hear one example of past simple
好，Marco，在我们开始讨论之前，我们先听一个一般过去时的例子
and one example of past progressive?
和一个过去进行时的例子。
You know, just last week, I ran into Matt as well.
你知道吗，就在上周，我也偶然遇见了Matt。
Well, we were talking and catching up on what we've been doing.
嗯，我们正在聊天，聊聊最近在做什么。
Okay, so we heard that just last week, I ran into Matt.
好，所以我们听到“就在上周，我偶然遇见了Matt”。
So we discussed what run into means.
我们讨论过run into的意思。
Yep, to meet someone by surprise.
是的，意外遇见某人。
All right.
好的。
And now this structure is the simple past, right?
那么这个结构就是一般过去时，对吧？
Yep.
是的。
Now the second example that we heard was, we were talking and catching up.
现在我们听到的第二个例子是，我们当时正在聊天叙旧。
Okay, so let's look at the difference in meaning here.
好的，那我们来看看这里意思上的区别。
I ran into Matt, happened in the past, right?
我偶遇了马特，这件事发生在过去，对吧？
Right, simple past.
对，一般过去时。
But one moment in the past.
但只是过去的一个时间点。
So the action finished, concluded.
所以这个动作完成了，结束了。
Started and finished all around the same time.
开始和结束几乎在同一时间。
So it's one simple moment.
所以它是一个简单的时间点。
Okay.
好的。
Now, the other example is in the past progressive.
现在，另一个例子是过去进行时。
So the action was happening for a longer period of time.
所以这个动作持续了更长的时间。
Yeah.
是的。
So let's attach some times to this.
那我们给这个加上一些时间点。
Maybe you ran into Matt at 8.04.
也许你在8点04分偶遇了马特。
Okay.
好的。
And so the action started at 8.04.
所以这个动作从8点04分开始。
But you were talking and catching up from 8.05 until 9.05.
但你们从8点05分一直聊天叙旧到9点05分。
Okay.
好的。
So you were talking for an hour.
所以你们聊了一个小时。
Right.
对。
So it's the past progressive you use when the action is happening for a longer period
所以当动作持续较长时间时，你就用过去进行时。
of time.
So to better understand this, let's have another example.
为了更好地理解这一点，我们再举一个例子。
Matt saw a mouse run under his chair and he completely lost it.
马特看到一只老鼠跑到他椅子下面，他完全失控了。
Everyone was staring and laughing.
大家都在盯着看并大笑。
So as we heard in the example, he saw a mouse run under his chair.
就像我们在例子中听到的，他看到一只老鼠跑到他椅子下面。
So a quick action that started and finished quickly.
所以这是一个快速开始并快速结束的动作。
Okay.
好的。
He saw the mouse and it ran under the chair.
他看到了老鼠，老鼠跑到了椅子下面。
Yeah.
是的。
Now, the second example we heard was, everyone was staring and laughing.
现在，我们听到的第二个例子是，大家都在盯着看并大笑。
So maybe this happened over four or five minutes.
所以这可能持续了四五分钟。
Okay.
好的。
So people were looking at him and laughing and talking about how he was screaming like
所以人们看着他，笑着，谈论他像女孩一样尖叫的样子。
a girl.
Yes.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
So that's the main difference between the simple past and the past progressive.
这就是一般过去时和过去进行时的主要区别。
The amount of time that the action happened.
动作发生的时间长度。
Yep.
是的。
All right.
好的。
Well, now that we understand a little bit more about the past tense, why don't we hear
好了，既然我们对过去时态有了更多了解，不如我们第三次听对话，在上下文中再听一遍。
it again in context by listening to the dialogue for a third time.
Mike, what's going on, man?
迈克，怎么了，老兄？
Long time no see.
好久不见。
Hey, Pat.
嘿，帕特。
Yeah.
是啊。
I haven't seen you in ages.
我好久没见到你了。
How's it going?
你怎么样？
Things are going great.
一切都很好。
It's funny running into you like this.
这样偶遇你真有意思。
Small world, huh?
世界真小，是吧？
You know, just last week I ran into Matt as well.
你知道吗，就在上周我也偶遇了马特。
Yeah.
是啊。
How's he doing?
他怎么样？
He's doing well.
他挺好的。
We went out for a couple of beers and the funniest thing happened.
我们出去喝了几杯啤酒，然后发生了最有趣的事。
Oh yeah?
哦，是吗？
Well, we were talking and catching up on what we've been doing, talking about work and family
嗯，我们当时正在聊天叙旧，聊着工作和家庭，
when all of a sudden Matt saw a mouse run under the chair and he completely lost it.
突然马特看到一只老鼠跑到椅子下面，他完全失控了。
He started freaking out and screaming.
他开始惊慌失措，尖叫起来。
Really?
真的吗？
Yeah.
是啊。
And the funniest thing was, then he jumped onto his chair and started shrieking like
最有趣的是，然后他跳上椅子，像女孩一样尖叫起来。
a girl.
He should have been there.
你真该在场。
Everyone was staring and laughing.
大家都在盯着看并大笑。
It was hilarious.
太搞笑了。
Okay.
好的。
Perfect.
完美。
So now that we understand the words and the grammar behind it, there are some interesting
好了，现在我们理解了单词和背后的语法，这里还有一些有趣的短语，你可以和朋友随意使用。
phrases here that you can use casually with your friends.
Yeah.
是的。
There's actually a lot of great sort of meeting and greeting and saying hello language.
实际上有很多很好的见面问候用语。
So for example, when they met up, since they were old friends, he said, Hey, Pat.
比如，当他们见面时，因为是老朋友，他说，嘿，帕特。
Hey.
嘿。
Okay.
好的。
So this word, hey.
所以这个词，嘿。
It's kind of like hi.
有点像嗨。
It's hi, right?
就是嗨，对吧？
Yep.
是的。
So you can use it to get somebody's attention, right?
所以你可以用它来引起别人的注意，对吧？
Like, Hey, I'm over here.
比如，嘿，我在这儿。
Hey, waiter.
嘿，服务员。
Okay.
好的。
Yeah.
是的。
But in this case, like, Hey, how's it going?
但在这个情况下，就像，嘿，你怎么样？
Or hi.
或者嗨。
Yeah.
是的。
So it's a really friendly and informal way of saying hi.
所以这是一种非常友好和非正式的说嗨的方式。
Okay.
好的。
And then he asked, how's it going?
然后他问，你怎么样？
How's it going?
你怎么样？
So again, this is a way of saying, how are you?
同样，这是一种说“你好吗？”的方式。
Yeah.
是的。
Marco, what's the correct answer to this greeting?
马可，对这个问候的正确回答是什么？
Well, well, for example, he said, things are going great.
嗯，比如，他说，一切都很好。
Right.
对。
You can say, yeah, things are great.
你可以说，是啊，一切都很好。
Or I'm doing well.
或者我挺好的。
Yeah.
是的。
Or even great.
甚至可以说很好。
Great.
很好。
Yeah.
是的。
So how's it going?
所以“你怎么样？”
Oh, it's great.
哦，很好。
Yeah.
是的。
Right.
对。
Now, another one that we didn't see in the dialogue, but it's very popular is when somebody
现在，另一个我们在对话中没有看到，但很常见的问候是，当有人问，嘿，怎么了？
asks, Hey, what's up?
Yeah.
是的。
What's up?
怎么了？
So again, what is the right way to answer this question?
同样，回答这个问题的正确方式是什么？
All right.
好的。
So when somebody says, what's up?
所以当有人说，怎么了？
You can say, well, not much.
你可以说，嗯，没什么。
Or if maybe you have news or something that you want to share, you would say, well, I
或者如果你有消息或想分享的事情，你会说，嗯，我刚从医生办公室回来。
just got back from the doctor's office.
Yeah.
是的。
But you wouldn't say, fine, thank you.
但你不能说，很好，谢谢。
Or you wouldn't say, very good.
或者你不能说，非常好。
Or any of these other common answers to what's up.
或者其他这些常见的回答。
That's right.
没错。
It can be a little bit tricky.
这可能有点棘手。
Yeah.
是的。
So the rule is, the normal thing to say when someone says, hey, what's up?
所以规则是，当有人说，嘿，怎么了？通常的回答是。
Is nothing much.
没什么。
Not much.
Yep.
是的。
All right.
好的。
So interesting ways of greeting casually with people, right?
所以这些是和朋友随意问候的有趣方式，对吧？
You wouldn't use this fully with your boss, maybe, or in an office setting.
你可能不会对老板或在办公室场合完全这样用。
Yeah.
是的。
More useful with your friends.
对朋友更有用。
Okay.
好的。
So if you have any other questions or have any other informal greetings that you would
所以如果你有其他问题，或者有其他非正式问候语想和我们分享，请来EnglishPod.com。
like to share with us, come to EnglishPod.com.
Yeah.
是的。
Marco and I are always around to answer your questions and we look forward to hearing from
马可和我随时都在回答你的问题，我们期待收到你的消息。
you.
So until next time.
所以下次再见。
Bye.
再见。
Have a great day.
祝你有美好的一天。